<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kentaro Kuribayashi</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/</link><description>Recent content on Kentaro Kuribayashi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 20:09:41 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kentarokuribayashi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mining the Connections</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/mining-the-connections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 20:09:41 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/mining-the-connections/</guid><description>“All the people have already connected each other” is a notable phrase said in “Serial Experiments Lain,” one of the representative Japanese animations in the 1990s. It showed a futuristic vision of the cyber world. We are able to, even now, take many ideas from it.
Not same as what the IoT brings, we now have a feeling, “all the things have already connected each other.” As I wrote before, future cyber-archeologists will mine the connections from digital garbage piled up on the cyberspace.</description></item><item><title>From Anthropocene to Cyberocene</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/from-anthropocene-to-cyberocene/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 02:38:19 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/from-anthropocene-to-cyberocene/</guid><description>The concept “Anthropocene”, initially coined by Paul J. Crutzen, has been increasing its importance among not only science world but also philosophy and art world. In the former, the word is referred along with speculative realism. In the latter, it is often referred as a next-generation concept to strategically confuse the boundary between human beings and other things.
The concept is intriguing not just because it brings a new way of thinking on how human beings have affected the Earth in terms of geology, but because it implies the world after human beings.</description></item><item><title>Preference to Logical and Abstract Thoughts</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/preference-to-logical-and-abstract-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 02:33:42 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/preference-to-logical-and-abstract-thoughts/</guid><description>I guess sometimes I could be happier if I had some hobby to have cameras, cars, or something that belong to masculine culture. It is formed by materials. Preference to collect such physical things features in men’s taste. I don’t have any interest in it, however, it could make me satisfied, though.
At the beginning, I don’t like to have materials. I rarely buy things. Furniture, clothes, shoes, home appliances, etc.</description></item><item><title>Learning Languages to Achieve Our Own Goals</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/learning-languages-to-achieve-our-own-goals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 02:31:29 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/learning-languages-to-achieve-our-own-goals/</guid><description>People often argue that speaking is the most important for learning languages, blaming traditional education for it has an excessive tendency to grammar that is not useful for “practical” usage of languages. I partly agree with them, that is, not completely.
I’d like to discuss the issue from another point of view. At the first place, since we are old enough, we must decide the way to learn by ourselves. Thus, whatever people say, the goal of learning must come from our need, not from others’.</description></item><item><title>Whicheverness: Beyond Dichotomy</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/whicheverness-beyond-dichotomy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 02:29:20 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/posts/whicheverness-beyond-dichotomy/</guid><description>Things pressure us to choose at least one of them. We are hardly able to leave them free without determining which is more preferable. If we hesitate to make up our mind to pick one up, we can’t avoid being regarded as indecisive. Those who tend to postpone determination can’t progress things. However, does choosing something always desirable?
Richard Rorty, one of the representative philosophers in the late Twenty Century, expressed his “split-up” between publicness and privateness in an impressive essay, “Trotsky and the Wild Orchids.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kentarokuribayashi.com/about/</guid><description>tl;dr; Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Kentaro Kuribayashi. Call me Kentaro.
Kentaro Kuribayashi is a Tokyo-based software engineer who has built a career in the Internet industry, and is also an art and book enthusiast.
He received a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Law from Tokyo Metropolitan University, Japan in 1999. From 2008, he started his actual career as a software engineer. He is now a board member of GMO Pepabo, Inc. and is in charge of technology and engineering as Chief Technology Officer(CTO).</description></item></channel></rss>